Just a single line of text.
Text extending over
two lines.
Text extending
over
three lines.
Line does not end with a period
because the sentence continues.
...line starting with dot-dot-dot.
…line starting with ellipsis.
Line ending with dot-dot-dot...
Line ending with ellipsis…
Line ending with four dots....
Line ending with ellipsis and a dot.
Line that has: a colon.
Line ends with number 1
1 number starts the line
Entire line in italics.
Only part of line in italics.
Two lines of text,
separately in italics.
Italics extending over
multiple lines.
- Dialog marked with minus sign.
- Different speaker.
– Dialog marked with en-dash.
– Different speaker.
— Dialog marked with em-dash.
— Different speaker.
- Dialog line in italics.
- Or part of it.
– First line in italics.
– Second not.
— First line regular.
— Second in italics.
♪ Song lyrics ♪
♪ Lyrics in italics ♪
♪ Lyrics partly in italics ♪
♪ Lyrics on two ♪
♪ separate lines ♪
♪ Lyrics extending over
two lines ♪
♪ – Dialog with en-dash ♪
♪ – Second singer ♪
♪ — Dialog with em-dash ♪
♪ — Second singer ♪
SPEAKER: Just a single line.
SPEAKER: Text extending
over two lines.
SPEAKER: But line has: a colon.
SPEAKER: But first line:
ends with a colon.
SPEAKER: Text in italics.
SPEAKER: Two lines
in italics.
separately in italics.
PAUL: Speaker 1 says.
MARY: Speaker 2 says.
PAUL: Is on-screen.
MARY: Is off-screen.
PAUL: Says something
MARY: Emphasizes this word.
PAUL & MARY: Two people speak.
PAUL & MARY:
Two people speak on new line.
SPEAKER: Says off-screen.
- On-screen person replies.
someone continues.
SPEAKER: New person says.
- Person speaks on-screen.
SPEAKER: Replies off-screen.